# 江苏·邳州
Pizhou. Jiangsu
# 咱们今天来吃的是牛肉拉面
Today we gonna have beef hand-pulled noodles
# 没想到正好赶上饭点 这屋子里的人是乌央乌央的
# 来两个小碗 再来一个凉拌牛肉
I want two bowls of hand-pulled noodle and a beef in sauce
# 20块钱牛肉行吗  行
20 yuan of beef? Okay
# 一共40块钱
40 yuan total
# 能吃辣椒吗
Can you eat spicy oil?
# 能吃辣椒 稍微放点就行
Yeah, a little bit
# 40块钱是吧
40 yuan right?
# 刚才没有问 牛肉多少钱一斤了
I forget to ask, how much beef is each half a kilo
# 没想到 10块钱的小碗竟然有这么多的牛肉
I didn’t expect    there is so many beef in the 10 yuan bowls
# 量特别足
With large amounts of beef
# 除了牛肉拉面之外呢 我们还要了一份凉拌牛肉
We ordered a beef in sauce besides hand-pulled beef noodles
# 一看上去就是辣椒 香菜 还有大片的牛肉
With spicy pepper, Chinese parsley, and big slices of beef
# 牛肉拉面嘛 咱们先尝一尝这边的牛肉
Let’s try beef first
# 牛肉都是切成大片的
They sliced beef into large slices
# 就是常温的牛肉 放在拉面里
Just homeothermy beef in hand-pulled noodle
# 加了一些的辣椒 好下饭
Good to eat with some spicy pepper,
# 我感觉面条里面可能也是加了盐
I think they add salts in the noodle
# 因为整体的拉面吃起来都是咸的
Because it taste salty
# 面馆里 满屋子都是吸溜面条的声音
Whole restaurant with sounds of sucking noodle
# 拉面的汤 是微辣 微咸和微香
The soup of noodle is with lighter spicy, lighter salty and lighter fragments
# 里面泡的牛肉 比凉拌的牛肉是更加软嫩的
The beef in the soup is softer and tender than the beef in sauce
# 因为牛肉泡了一些汤汁嘛
Because there’s soup in the beef
# 这么吃起来就是 毫不费力
Very easy to eat
# 大叔 您怎么想到做牛肉拉面呢
Uncle, how do you start the hand-pulled beef noodles?
# 牛肉拉面 甘肃吃牛肉拉面
Hand-pulled beef noodle is popular in Gansu
# 我就跟甘肃学的
I learned it in Gansu
# 就是引进了甘肃牛肉拉面的做法
Import Gansu hand-pulled beef noodle style
# 做的味道适合咱们本地人的口味
And changed it to fit local flavor
# 兰州拉面到我们这地方干不起来
Local people don’t like Lanzhou hand-pulled noodle style
# 毕竟口味不同
Because it is different
# 口味 我们做的是地方口味
We make local flavor
# 这边除了卖拉面还有什么
What else you have except hand-pulled noodle?
# 就一样拉面 别的什么都没有
Just hand-pulled noodle, nothing else
# 只有一种牛肉 一种面就是拉面
Only a type of beef and a type of noodle which is hand-pulled noodle
# 每天都这么热闹吗
Is it as crowded every day?
# 全都这么热闹
Yeah, it is
# 天凉比现在还热闹 天冷比这更热闹
# 一年到头都干吗
Are you work whole year?
# 夏天三个月不干
Not three month of summer
# 夏天为什么三个月不干
Why don’t?
# 夏天我这里面热 夏天太热了 受不了 没法开空调
Because it's too hot in summer, can not stand it without air conditioning
# 没法安空调
Can not have air conditioning
# 这个时候吃完饭 都是脑门子上直冒汗
Sweat all over head after you finish eat in summer
# 过几天天气更热
It’s get hotter after couple days
# 吃完拉面可能就是一种酣畅淋漓的状态了
# 后面是刚熬完辣椒油
Just finish cook chili oil at back
# 站在这么远的地方 还能够闻到呛鼻辣椒的味道
You still can smell chili even if you stand so far
# 别看只是一口小锅在这个地方熬辣椒油
# 还能吸引一大帮子人在这个地方看热闹
# 这真不错 酒厂拉面谁不知道
This is good, who don’t know winery hand-pulled noodle
# 你经常来吃这个拉面吗
Do you come often?
# 嗯 经常来
Yeah, always
# 在这儿吃多少年了
How many years you eat here?
# 十几年了
More than ten years
# 我都30了
I’m 30 years old
# 刚才和师傅聊天的时候 他说
The master said that
# 这边牛肉拉面的做法是从甘肃引进过来 学习过来的
The way to make hand-pulled noodle is import from Gansu
# 但是它们的口味还是有很大的不同的
With huge difference of flavor
# 听了这个 我倒是很想去甘肃这边看一看
I want to go to Gansu and take a look
# 那边的牛肉拉面是什么样子的呢
What does it look like?
# 关 注
雪 鱼 探 店